I believe we have a choice in this
world about how to tell sad stories.
On the one hand,
you can sugarcoat it.
The way they do in movies
and romance novels...
where beautiful people
learn beautiful lessons...
where nothing is too messed
up that can't be fixed...
with an apology
and a Peter Gabriel song.
I like that version as much
as the next girl does,
believe me.
It's just not the truth.
This is the truth.
Sorry.
Late in the winter
of my seventeenth year...
my mother decided
that I was depressed.
She just eats like a bird,
she barely leaves the house.
I am not depressed, Mom.
She's reading the same
book over and over.
She's depressed.
I'm not depressed.
The booklets and the websites
always list depression as
a side effect of cancer.